{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Lactobacilli grow best under", "opta": "strict anaerobic conditions", "optb": "microaerophilic conditions in presence of 5% CO2 and PH6", "optc": "microaerophilic conditions in presence of 3% CO2 and PH5", "optd": "microaerophilic conditions in presence of 2% CO2 and PH4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following genera is included in the family Bacteroi-daceae?", "opta": "Bacteroides", "optb": "Fusobacterium", "optc": "Leptotrichia", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteria which is predominant flora of the human gut is", "opta": "Escherichia coli", "optb": "Clostridium perfringens", "optc": "Bacteroides", "optd": "Actinomyces", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The current genus name of a saccharolytic group of Bacteroides is", "opta": "Porphyromonas", "optb": "Bacteroides", "optc": "Prevotella", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Colonies resembling molar teeth are produced by", "opta": "Nocardia brasiliensis", "optb": "N. asteroids", "optc": "Actinomyces israelii", "optd": "Actinomadura madurae", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacterial colonies fluoresce brick-red in UV light?", "opta": "B gingivalis", "optb": "B melaninogenicus", "optc": "Bacteroides fragilis", "optd": "B levii", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria is acid-fast?", "opta": "Actinomyces", "optb": "Nocardia", "optc": "Streptomyces", "optd": "Corynebacterium", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lactobacilli constitute the normal flora of", "opta": "prepubertal vagina", "optb": "adult vagina", "optc": "post-menopausal vagina", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria is gram-negative cocci?", "opta": "Veillonella", "optb": "Peptococcus", "optc": "Peptostreptococcus", "optd": "Sporosarcina", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commonest species of Bacteroides in fragilis group, which causes human infection, is", "opta": "B vulgatus", "optb": "B fragilis", "optc": "B ovatus", "optd": "B merdae", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commonest bacterial cause of cervicofacial actinomycosis is", "opta": "A. naeslundii", "optb": "A. viscosus", "optc": "A. israelii", "optd": "A. meyeri", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria is moderately saccharolytic?", "opta": "Bacteriodes fragilis", "optb": "B gingivalis", "optc": "B melaninogenicus", "optd": "B levii", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}